News announcer
The fourth major hurricane of the season
slams the Jacksonville beach
and points north and south along the Florida-Georgia coastline.
Winds of 100 miles an hour and upwards...
Narrator
People have long known the destructive nature of hurricanes.
These storms, bringing heavy winds and rain
may last several hours
and have a diameter of over 480 kilometers, or 300 miles.
Hurricanes form over warm tropical oceans
in areas of low air pressure.
They consist of high-velocity winds blowing in a circular motion
around a low-pressure center known as the eye of the storm.
The only defense against hurricanes
is through early warning and preparation.
Meteorologists can now track these storms
and measure their force through the use of radar and satellites.
Meteorologist
It looks like now the center will pass inland sometime near dawn.
As it goes across the Florida peninsula
of course we're going to have significant damage here
in Miami-Fort Lauderdale area.
Narrator
The National Hurricane Center's prediction was correct.
In August 1992
Hurricane Andrew caused billions of dollars in damage
and killed a number of people
when it hit the southeastern United States.